Thank you so much for joining us. I have the privilege this morning of introducing
you to a new friend of mine. One thing that we've been really intentional about as a church is, although I am the senior pastor, and I'm a little bit more senior today than I was yesterday. I planned that one. I intentionally preach just a little bit over 50% because we believe that this is not my church, this is Christ's church, and that we hear God's voice primarily through community with one another.
It gives us the unique opportunity to hear from voices in our own congregation that have the gifting of preaching and teaching. It also gives me the really unique honor to introduce you to people that I get connected with in my relationships as a pastor, people that are incredibly gifted and knowledgeable and wise. Today is one of those days when you get to meet one of my friends who is gifted and talented and wise. I'd love for you to give a warm welcome to my new friend, Shawna Rushing.
Shawna Rushing, who is the small groups pastor of a church called New Life Fellowship in Queens, New York. So she's very brave to come all the way down here to Frederick County. So give her a warm welcome and we'd love to hear from you.
Thank you so much, Ryan. Good morning, everybody. It really is an honor and a privilege to get to share with you to preach God's word.
to you this morning, and I love being here. It's gorgeous. My friend Vicki came with me this morning and we got to stay in a beautiful cabin in the woods and it was very good for my soul. I need to get out of the city. I did not grow up in New York City. I've been there for two years. I love being there. I serve at an incredibly global church. We have 75 nations represented in our church and that's really indicative of Queens. Queens is
I think the most global zip code in the country, if not the world. So it's a wonderful, wonderful place to be and to worship with people from all over the world. And as I said, it's a wonderful privilege to be here with you. I'm an ordained brethren pastor, so I'm also thrilled to be at a brethren church this morning. I'll try and throw in a little brethren theology for you every now and then. But I really
love talking about the Holy Spirit. I actually began to encounter the Holy Spirit as an elementary school student. And I'm grateful for that because I didn't have my adult boxes. And so I was really open to God moving in unique ways as a kid. And God would even give me dreams about friends.
That I would begin praying for. And so I didn't plan this, but I just want to say to any teens in the room, your kids that are outside and parents, God is speaking to children and to teens in profound ways. And they have something to teach us.
And so, teens, I see you on the front row. The Holy Spirit has something to say to you. The Holy Spirit is speaking and moving, and you have something to teach us. Okay? And adults in the room, the Holy Spirit has something to say to you today. The Holy Spirit has something very intentional for each one of us
in the room. Vicki and I have been praying a lot in the car as we drive, and I'm excited. And so, I hope you're open. I hope you're open and ready for what the Holy Spirit wants to do today in this place as a gift. It's a gift. Okay? So, let's pray in that vein. And we're going to do something different. I like to do a lot of prayer practices. I like embodied practices.
I like to pray on my breath. So, we're going to start with what's called a breath prayer. The Holy Spirit is called breath. Okay? God gives us breath. And so, a breath prayer is simply praying internally on your breath. So, as we inhale, we're going to pray, "Welcome." And on our exhale, we're going to pray internally, Holy Spirit. Okay? It's really easy. Very simple.
And we're going to do that several times, and I'll pray an opening prayer for us. So, if you're willing to close your eyes, and begin to center on your breath, taking some slow, deep inhales and exhales, and then we're going to add in our breath prayer. Inhaling. Welcome.
Exhaling. Holy Spirit. Do that a couple times at your own pace.
We do welcome and honor your presence, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.
We pray that this would be a sacred time and space for us to hear from You, to encounter You.
We pray this would be a protected space. Would You surround us with Your angels?
Would You shine Your light and push back all darkness?
Holy Spirit, would You purify our minds and our imaginations,
that we might see what You're doing? Would You tune our ears to Your voice, God,
to hear all that You want to say? And God, would You remove any obstacle that would get in the way of us
receiving all that You have for us? Pray that You'd remove any obstacle in me that would get in the way
of what You want to say and do this morning. We say we're dependent on You, Holy Spirit. Have Your way
in this place. Amen. Amen. So I want you all to think about a time when you needed someone to come
alongside you, a time when you were in distress, maybe really sick, maybe having a lot of anxiety or in
depression, a time when you really were not doing well on your own, in your own strength, and you needed
someone to come beside you and help you, maybe advocate for you. I've been thinking about that
this week, and I've had many of those times in my life, but the one that I just couldn't get past
and seemed to be highlighted the most was actually when I was pregnant with my youngest daughter. I
have three kids. My oldest daughter, so my first child, and I had had a really difficult pregnancy
with her, and when I went into labor, I ended up being in labor for 40 hours. It was very long and hard,
and don't worry, guys. I'm not going to get too graphic here, but I do want to share a little
bit about this because I had a phenomenal nurse midwife who came alongside me in that very challenging
labor, and where things got distressing because Emmy wasn't doing well, and, you know, they were
talking about an emergency cesarean, and my body was just so exhausted, and I needed to figure out,
you know, how to deliver this baby, and this nurse midwife coached me through. I didn't know what I
was doing. Again, I was exhausted, and you know what? She did not praise me. She was
she did comfort me, and she supported me, but she did not praise me if I wasn't doing something
productive to deliver my baby, but when I did, she let me know, and that's how I learned, "Oh, I'm doing
the right thing. I'm doing the right thing," and so that nurse midwife was crucial in coming alongside
me in helping me birth my beautiful daughter and bring new life into the world. So why am I telling
you this story? I'm telling you this story because the Holy Spirit, the paraclete, is the advocate, and so
I want to bring up that first slide, okay? So the Holy Spirit comes alongside us,
comes to our aid, okay? And in the New Testament, we see this in an active sense, one who appears on
another's behalf, a mediator, an intercessor, a helper. Is there anybody in this room that could use
an advocate, an intercessor, a helper, and not just any advocate or helper, one that we have access to 24
hours a day, one that is indwelling us? Anybody need access? Anybody want to pay attention to an advocate
that's been given to us as a gift? I know I do. I need the Holy Spirit. So this word, parakletos,
is translated in different translations. You know, as is often the case, it's hard to just translate
directly in English. So we see in different versions, it may be the comforter, the counselor,
the advocate, the helper. I like all those words. I need all those. I need a helper. I need an advocate.
I need a counselor. I need a comforter. So today we're talking about who is the Holy Spirit, right?
And there's a lot I could say about who is the Holy Spirit. Our Bible starts, second verse,
Genesis 1:2. We see the Holy Spirit hovering over the chaos and the darkness, ready to bring order
in life and flourishing. So from the beginning, the Holy Spirit, who is God? I need to say that when we
say, "Who is the Holy Spirit?" The Holy Spirit is God, our triune God, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, okay? But today,
I can't tell you everything Scripture has to say about the Holy Spirit. We would be here for a long time.
But I will say this. I brought you a worksheet. If we have any students, and when I say student,
I mean people who just like to get in the Word or really like to dig in deeper, I brought you a
worksheet, okay, that has more that I can't get into today. But you are welcome to take that with you
and do more study. I hope you will. I had a great time. We have a foundations class at our church, and
I got to develop this class on the Holy Spirit. And so that's what I, I already had the worksheet. So I'm
sharing it with you, and I hope you enjoy it. But what I want to really focus on today is what Jesus had to say
about the Holy Spirit. You guys interested in what Jesus had to say about the Holy Spirit?
Okay. And you know, when we talk about the Holy Spirit, we often go to Luke and Acts and to Pentecost,
which is fantastic. But today we're actually going to focus on the book of John, because there's a ton
of theology about the Holy Spirit, because Jesus talks a lot about the Holy Spirit in the book of
John. So we're going to do a quick overview, and then we're going to focus in on a few chapters. But
I want to say, John chapter 3, Jesus has this encounter with a guy named Nicodemus,
and he tells Nicodemus, "You can't enter the kingdom of God without being born of water and spirit." And
then he starts talking about the Holy Spirit, and he says, "You know the wind? The wind that you can't
control, and you don't know where it's going? That's what the Holy Spirit is like." And friends, I know
that sometimes that's why we get uncomfortable with the Holy Spirit, because if you're anything
like me, I like things to be controlled. I like to know what's coming. I want to put things in a nice,
tidy box, but that's not how the Holy Spirit is. And actually, that's really exciting and fun,
if we can open ourselves up to the movement of the Holy Spirit, and that we can trust
that our perspective is very limited, and that we have a really big God who wants to do far more than
we could ever ask or imagine, that wants to work in ways that are much bigger and cooler than what we
could come up with. But that means we have to be open for the Spirit to blow, and to blow in ways and
directions that we're not anticipating, and we might not even like. Okay? So Jesus starts pushing on this
early with Nicodemus, a religious leader, right? He's pushing. I want you to know it's going to blow
in ways that you can't control. Are you open to that this morning? Are you open to that?
Okay. John 7, Jesus says this. He says, "Is anyone thirsty? Let them come to me." And then he says, "From within them
will flow rivers of living water." Let me put my glasses on here. "Now, he said this about the Spirit,
whom those who believed in him were going to receive. For the Spirit had
not yet been given because Jesus was not yet glorified." So he's preparing them. The Spirit
is coming, and the Spirit is going to well up within you like rivers of living water. Are you thirsty
for that? Yesterday, Vicki and I, my parents live in Harrisburg, so dropped my kids off with the
grandparents, and we really wanted to go on a hike because it's so beautiful. And we knew between there
and here is tons of hiking and just beautiful trees and mountains, and so we found a hike called
Pole Steeple Trail. And there's a lake at the bottom, and my parents have told us that there's actually this
spout that is sticking out of the mountain that's connected to this mountain spring. And there's like
a line of cars that are lined up next to this spout, and people are bringing all kinds of jugs
of water because this water is so fresh, so clean, so mineral rich, and it's free. You know how much you
can spend just buying filtered water, right, at the grocery store? This is just unlimited, the best kind
of, I mean seriously, like we had some, just so refreshing, so good, unending supply, and that's the
Holy Spirit. Rivers of living water wanting to flow through us. This is getting good, right?
All right, there's more. Where I want us to focus is three chapters, John 14 to 16, and what's happening
here is Jesus has just met in the upper room with his disciples and washed their feet, and they've
taken the bread and the cup together, and he's said, "One of you is going to betray me." You know, and Judas
leaves. And then after that, Jesus has these words that he wants to give to his disciples, his last
parting words, the most important things he wants to share with them. Let's think about this like maybe
when you're sending one of your kids off to live on their own for the first time or to go to college,
and what are the most important things that you want to impart to them? You want to say, you want them to
know as they leave your nest. So Jesus' disciples are about to leave the nest, and they're about to go
through a lot. And he's got some really important things to say. By the way, before we get into that,
I heard you guys are preparing for a love feast. Is that right? So I just want to say, the love feast
is such a special, sacred time of communion with Jesus and
and with each other. And it's one of my favorite things that the Brethren Church does. So I hope
that you all will participate. It will be a beautiful experience, and I'm really excited
about it for you. Super. I wish I could be there. So let's look. What did Jesus say? He had a lot to
say about the Holy Spirit. He had a lot to say about some other things in these three passages. But I want
to focus on what he's saying about the Holy Spirit. And what we're going to see here is that he's repeating
two names of the Holy Spirit a number of times. And the first is one we've already talked about.
The paracletos, the advocate, the counselor, the helper. Okay? So, and I will ask the Father,
and he will give you another advocate to help you and be with you forever. So not only do we have
this 24-hour access to this advocate, counselor, comforter, helper, but he's going to be with us
forever. What an encouragement. Jesus also says, "But the advocate, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father
will send in my name, will teach you all things and will remind you of everything I have said to you."
So the Holy Spirit is a teacher. And one thing I want to say about this, you know, the disciples,
they had been with Jesus. And so he's saying, "The Holy Spirit's going to remind you
of the things I said, the things I taught you, the things I showed you." And as Christians,
we obviously have this beautiful book where we get to learn the things Jesus said. But if we don't read
this book, if we don't hide these things in our heart, it's going to be really hard for the Holy
Spirit to pull them to mind at the right time. Okay? So we need this. And here's another Brethren theology
for you. In the Brethren Church, we call the Holy Spirit the inner word. Okay? This is the outer word,
Scripture. The Holy Spirit is the inner word. That is going to remind us of everything that Jesus said.
It's going to remind us of the truth of Scripture. Okay, let's keep going. "When the Advocate comes,
whom I will send to you from the Father, the Spirit of truth, who goes out from the Father,
He will testify about me." What I want you to know is that the Holy Spirit is always testifying to Jesus.
The Holy Spirit is always highlighting Jesus. That's a role of the Holy Spirit. And that's a part of how we
can discern spirits too, right? That the Holy Spirit is always testifying and highlighting Jesus.
And lastly here, "But very truly, I tell you, it is for your good that I'm going away." Right?
These are Jesus's words to His disciples. It's for your good. Can you imagine what that must have been
like to hear that? I mean, how connected they are to Jesus, how dependent they are on Him, that they're
giving their whole life to follow Him, and He's telling them, "Actually, it's better if I'm not here
anymore." That would be really hard to hear. "But it's for your good that I'm going away. Unless I go away,
the Advocate will not come to you. But if I go, I will send Him to you." And the Holy Spirit's not
going to be limited in one human body, right? The Holy Spirit can be poured out on all flesh. So that's
exciting. Let's read it through. So we've got the Advocate. The Holy Spirit is the Advocate. And Jesus
also wants us to know, and we'll go to the next slide, that the Holy Spirit is the Spirit of truth.
Okay? So Jesus repeats this in three chapters three times. And I will ask the Father, we've already seen
some of this in the Scriptures before, and He will give you another Advocate to help you, and will be
with you forever, the Spirit of truth. When the Advocate comes, whom I will send to you from the
Father, the Spirit of truth, the inner Word, who goes out from the Father, He will testify about me.
But when He, the Spirit of truth, comes, He will guide you into all truth.
Do you think we need to be guided into truth right now?
I really need the Spirit of truth to come and give me discernment about what is true and what is not.
We need that. And He says He will. He will guide you into all truth. He will not speak on His own.
He will speak only what He hears, and He will tell you what is yet to come. So we have an advocate,
and we have a Spirit of truth that is testifying to Jesus, that is our inner Word with us at all times,
that is revealing the truth to us that we desperately need to be paying attention to.
And you know what's interesting? When I was studying this, it suddenly hit me. You know,
the Holy Spirit is called the advocate and the Spirit of truth, but Satan is called the accuser and the
father of lies. Okay? So Satan is the exact opposite of the Holy Spirit who is advocating.
In Hebrew, Satan means the accuser. We see in Revelation, I hear you're talking about that a
little bit. Satan is called the accuser of the brethren. He is coming after the people of God to
accuse. And so I wonder, who are you listening to? Who are you yielding to?
I want to tell you a story about that in my own life. So when I was turning 40,
I decided I was going to meet two of my best college friends in Chicago, have a girls weekend, super
excited. So my friends are flying in. I lived in Ohio at the time. I was going to drive there. So I got
there a little bit early, and I decided I was going to stop at a Whole Foods and get a salad and wait a
little bit. So I'm there. I'm sitting at a table. I'm eating my salad, minding my own business. I've never
been to this Whole Foods in my life or this area. And I suddenly noticed that there's a teenage girl
sitting, you know, at a couple tables ahead of me. And all of a sudden, I just had this—I was overcome
by the love of God for her. Like, just—this is not me. I, like, just cannot shake this. I'm sensing just
so—this huge outpouring of God's love for her. And I'm like, "Lord, what is this? Are you—do you want
me to talk to her?" You know, and I'm sensing yes. And I'm saying, "Okay, I am a weird mom.
Like, she does not want to talk to me. Like, this—this is so awkward, Lord." Like, I—you know, and just pressing and just,
"Okay, so I know I need to talk to her. I don't exactly know what's going to come out of my mouth or how it's
going to go, but I just get the courage to go over to her, and I just say, you know, I know you don't
know me, but as I was sitting there, and I saw you, I was just so overcome by God's love for you, and I
just really want you to know how much God sees you, and He loves you." And she immediately broke into tears,
and she started to tell me that she's a Christian, and that she's really struggling with her family who
aren't believers, and she's been struggling in her faith and questioning, you know, whether she should
keep pressing in or not, and that was just such an important encounter and reminder for me, and that
was a simple thing. I didn't tell, I didn't have like secret information about her or anything like that,
but I just had a very strong impression that I knew didn't come from me, and you know,
I asked God about it, and it was like, yeah, you need to talk to this person, and I may never,
I probably will never see that person again. I may never be in that location again, but the Holy Spirit
was doing something. The Holy Spirit was at work in this person long before I ever showed up,
but the Holy Spirit invited me to join in with what God was already doing, and thank goodness I didn't
listen to the, "She doesn't want to hear this. Why would she want to hear what a mom has to say to her
right now?" And I said, "Okay, I'm going to take a risk, and I'm just going to share this." And I'll
never forget that moment, because it was beautiful, and God obviously wanted her to know, "I see you.
I love you." And He wants to use you in those ways. The Holy Spirit wants to speak to you.
And here's the thing about the advocate. The advocate does advocate for you. He advocates for you
in others as well. But the advocate also wants to advocate for others through you.
So in that moment, the Holy Spirit was advocating for that beautiful young girl.
I want her to know. Tell her. I want her to know
how much I love her and how much I see her. And that was the advocate, advocating for her.
Okay? So you want to let the Holy Spirit become an advocate in you or others
to your neighbors next door with big scary monsters in their front yard.
Okay? The Holy Spirit wants you to be an advocate with Him. That's exciting. That's exciting.
So we know the Holy Spirit's an advocate. We know the Holy Spirit's the Spirit of truth. What I want
you to know is that the Holy Spirit empowers us. Okay? The Holy Spirit wants to empower you. There's
a few things I want to say about this, and this is going to be quick because I don't have a ton of
time. I'm just going to kind of overview. So I have one slide about the empowerment of the Holy Spirit.
Is it there? Or did I not put it?
Keep going. That's it. Thank you. Woohoo. Okay. So here's what I want you to know. As Christians,
we are a dwelling place, right, for the Spirit of God. If we follow Jesus, we are given the gift of
the Holy Spirit, and we are temples of the Holy Spirit. Okay. Scripture tells us. And we are also
commanded in Ephesians 5 to continually be filled with the Spirit. Okay. When it says be filled with
the Spirit, it's a present continuous tense, which means keep on being filled. Today, I need a fresh
infilling of the Holy Spirit. Today, you need a fresh infilling of the Holy Spirit. And did you know
that the same Spirit that raised Jesus from the dead is alive in you? This is the kind of power,
dead things coming alive kind of power, that we have access to. Okay. The same power that raised Jesus
from the dead is alive in you. Look it up. Romans 8. All right. And the Holy Spirit, we've been talking
about the Holy Spirit is a gift, and the Holy Spirit loves to pour out gifts on us. Okay. Those are gifts
that might blow in ways that make you uncomfortable. Those are gifts that might be outside of your box,
gifts like speaking in tongues, gifts like words of knowledge, words of wisdom, words of prophecy,
discernment of spirits. This is all scriptural. This is how God moves. So I want to be open to that,
and I've experienced that. I've experienced physical healing myself, people praying for me and being
physically healed. I've experienced praying for people and them being physically healed. I've had a
lot of experience with the Spirit coming, bringing emotional healing, the Holy Spirit coming through
dreams, the Holy Spirit telling me something about someone that I would never know. And I'm like,
"Oh my gosh." Again, what? You want me to do what? Okay, Lord. Let me share this. I don't know if this
is right. You know, sometimes we say that maybe it was like bad chili I had last night, but let me just
share this. If it's helpful, great. But the Spirit does things like this. We need the Spirit to do that.
And friends, the Holy Spirit is moving among the church today with the same power as in the early
church in the book of Acts. And I'm not sure how much you've seen that in this context. And this is
what's interesting, because it's challenging in the Western church, because the Western churches
are declining. But did you know that the global church is experiencing really unprecedented growth,
particularly in the global South, in Africa, and Asia? And do you know where the greatest growth is
happening? Among charismatics. That's where the growth of Christianity is happening today, among people who
are desperate for the Spirit of God to move, among people who need the Holy Spirit. Maybe today is
actually the International Day of Prayer for the persecuted church. Do you think the persecuted
church needs a helper and an advocate every moment to endure, to know, should I give the Bible to
someone and this may cost me my life? We in the Western church need to have a greater focus and
openness to the Holy Spirit. And perhaps we would experience greater growth if we did. I'm just
saying, okay? I'm just saying. And here's what the Holy Spirit, there's something called the fruit of
the Spirit. Do you guys sing about this? Love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness,
gentleness, and self-control. When we yield to the Holy Spirit in our life, the Spirit of truth,
we begin to have fruit that looks like love, that looks like self-control. And I do want to say this,
the Holy Spirit empowers me maybe to go talk to someone or to pray for healing for someone. But
you know what the Holy Spirit often empowers me to do? To shut up. The Holy Spirit often empowers me to
keep my mouth shut. Don't go there, Shauna. Nope. I know you want to have the last word right now, but you
need to zip it. So let's be open to that too. Okay. Okay, so let's get a little practical.
What do we do? How do we learn how to follow the leading of the Holy Spirit? If this is new for you,
or if maybe it's not, you know, I'm still learning. What are some ways that we can learn to follow the
leading of the advocate, the helper, the spirit of truth inside of us? I've got four L's in pastoral
alliteration style for you. Okay. Four L's. So here's the first one. We need to look.
If we don't think the Holy Spirit is at work right now and present, moving, why would we pay attention?
If we don't recognize that there's an advocate inside of us, we're not going to be noticing.
So we have to look. We need to ask for greater, got a little spelling error there, sorry, greater
awareness of the advocate helper within you and eyes to see what the Holy Spirit is already doing around
you. What has God already been doing in this city? What's the Holy Spirit already been doing in your
workplace? What does the Holy Spirit want to do now through you? What is the Holy Spirit already doing
in your kids? Have you stopped to look and notice so that you can join in with what the Holy Spirit's already
doing? We've got to look. We need to have eyes. Ask for eyes to see. Awareness is huge, right? A lot of
times we say, "First up is awareness." Okay? We've got to look. Okay, next thing. We need to listen.
And in order to really hear and to listen, we need to slow down.
Okay? If I'm in a swirl of all my to-dos and my to-do list, and I'm not willing to be interrupted,
or I'm not willing to take time, I'm going to miss it. I do miss it.
So we have got to take regular time to be still and quiet enough to listen for the direction and the
movement of the Holy Spirit in and around you. Holy Spirit, what are you doing right now?
What do you have? I have an agenda. I know what I want to do, but I'm going to lay that down right now.
What do you want to do, Holy Spirit? We're going to look. We're going to listen.
We're going to learn. Okay? So we know the Holy Spirit's the Spirit of truth. So when we come to
Scripture, the Spirit who empowered the writers of this text, we want to say, "Holy Spirit, give me fresh
revelation of truth." Maybe the way I was taught to understand this is limited, or I'm not seeing what
you want me to see. Open my eyes to illuminate what you want me to see here. And not only that,
you know, one of the ways I really learned to grow in the Spirit was from others who I saw yielding to
the guidance of the Holy Spirit. God, you know, I wanted to be around people. I had a friend,
we worked at a camp together, and she was like a fiery redhead. She was so fun. But like, wherever
we went, she was just talking. She was just talking to people. She was praying for people. She was like,
"We're in the car. Holy Spirit, what do you want to do?" And I was so encouraged and convicted
about the way she lived her life, because she was just in this constant communion with the Holy
Spirit and what the Holy Spirit was doing. And so it just really bolstered and grew my faith to be with
her and to watch her generation. She would just give things away. You know, I just feel like God wants
me to give you this. You know, she just was amazing. So get around some people who are yielding to the Holy
Spirit and learn and grow together. It's a beautiful way to learn to follow the leading of the Holy
Spirit. And the last L I want to give you is lean in. Okay? When we feel like the Holy Spirit is blowing
in a certain way and it makes us uncomfortable, we might want to go like this. I don't know about that.
I don't feel good about that. I'm slowly backing away. But what I want to invite you to do is to lean in.
With expectation. That the Holy Spirit wants to do something right now. And with obedience. I don't
understand this. This makes me really uncomfortable. But I want to yield to you, the advocate, and not to
the accuser who's telling me, "I don't have what it takes." I want to lean into you, advocate, who says,
"I've empowered you. I know you feel inadequate, but I'm empowering you. So take a step. Lean in."
Okay. John Wimber, who is known for really going with the moves of the Spirit, he says this. He says,
"Faith is spelled R-I-S-K." So if we start following the Holy Spirit, we're going to have to take some risks.
We're going to have to take some risks, like talking to strangers and Whole Foods. Okay. Are you ready for that? Are you open to that? Can we pray into that? Because I'd like to do that right now as we begin to wrap up. Okay. Yeah. Worship team, love for you to join me.
So here's what we're going to do. I told you I like to do prayer practices. I like to do things that are embodied. So there's a practice I like to do. It's a Quaker practice, and it's very simple. It's called "Palms Down, Palms Up." And I often envision that Jesus is standing before me, and I put my palms down. And, you know, it says in Scripture that we can cast every care on Him because He cares for us.
And so I just named to Jesus those anxieties or fears. But today what I want us to do that around is, I want us, with our palms down, and we're not going there yet, I'm just giving you instructions right now, I want us to name to Jesus any doubts maybe you're holding. Maybe you don't like anything I had to say today. Maybe it's just rubbing you all the wrong ways.
Just tell that to Jesus, okay? I want you to hear from Him way more than me. Okay? So we're just going to tell Him, "Jesus, this is my issue with the Holy Spirit." Or, "This is where I'm struggling."
Maybe it's, I've been listening to the accuser, and the accuser says, "God's speaking to everyone else but not me." So whatever it is,
I want you guys to pour that out in that time. And after we spend a little time naming that to Jesus,
and I'm going to invite you to turn your palms over, and that's a symbol that I'm open. And I'm ready, Jesus,
for you to show me who the Holy Spirit really is. And that I want to be open to whatever the Holy Spirit is doing,
however the Holy Spirit is blowing. I want to be open to that. And help me, helper. Helper, help me.
Wherever you are, wherever you are, because, you know, we can come to Jesus wherever we are.
We can come to Jesus with our doubts. We can come to Jesus with our unbelief, with our fear, with our
anxiety, with our desire to just hold our, you know, hands so tight and clenched. We can come just like that.
We're going to call on the helper to help us. Can we do that together right now?
So if you're willing and comfortable, I want you to close your eyes.
And we thank you, Holy Spirit, that you're here.
Thank you that you're moving. Thank you that you're speaking.
We pray that you would give us a sense or even a picture that Jesus is standing before us with his hands open, ready and waiting for us to come just as we are, with our doubts, our fears, with our desire for control.
We just want to turn our palms down, maybe even seeing ourselves putting our hands in the hands of Jesus, and beginning to name to Jesus any obstacle, anything that's really making it hard for us to engage right now, or to take a step towards faith.
Take your time. Jesus wants to hear it all.
Let's pray.
I want you to know that Jesus is looking on you with eyes of love. Receiving and listening to every word.
You can continue to release and pour out to Jesus as long as you need. And whenever you feel ready, you feel like you've poured out what you need to, you're welcome to turn your palms over as a symbol that you're ready and open to receive the gift and the gifts of the Holy Spirit.
Ready and open for Jesus to reveal and show you the Advocate Spirit of Truth.
Holy Spirit, you're welcoming. Come flood this place and fill the atmosphere.
Thank you, Jesus, for your words to the disciples when you said, "Peace, I leave with you. Receive my Holy Spirit."
We pray now that you would give us a fresh infilling of your Holy Spirit.
We want to lean in with expectation and obedience to what you're doing right now, Holy Spirit, and what you want to do in us and through us.
We pray that we would have a sense of the rivers of living water, rivers of living water flowing through and around us.
The resurrection power that brings death to life, that you would be bringing new life, Holy Spirit, into places in us that have been hardened and dead,
and numb. We need fresh and filling in life right now.
We're going to continue to just remain open and to worship together.
I'm going to join the prayer team with Vicki and Ryan. If you would like prayer, maybe for more of the Holy Spirit,
or you're experiencing resistance, or any general prayer requests that you have, it's open for anyone to come and receive prayer.
We'd love for you to pray, and we'll continue to listen and watch, to look, to listen, to learn, and to lean in
through what the Holy Spirit is doing right now and in the days to come. Amen.
Thank you.